Dorothy Thompson Papers
Dorothy Thompson Papers
- Outgoing correspondence
  - Oct 1951, 11 items (Box 38)
    Recipients: Melville Cane, Dorothy Culbertson, Vincent Sheean
  - Nov 1951, 29 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, "Dawn's Early Light", Reader's Digest
    Recipients: Karl Brandt, Cornelius Van Engert, Edgar Ansel Mowrer, Dale Warren
  - Dec 1951, 19 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Syracuse University, W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: Melville Cane, William P. Tolley, Dale Warren
  - Jan 1952, 29 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Foreign Affairs, Middle East, W.O.M.A.N., "Women's Manifesto", Writing
    Recipients: Abaullah Ibrahim Baker, Bernard Berenson, Millar Burrows, Winston Churchill, Mary Hughes, Alfred Lilienthal, Grace Sims Peat, Eleanor Roosevelt, Tolstoy Foundation, Inc., Lawrence Westbrook
  - Feb 1952, 28 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Franchon Arthur, Catholicism, Communism, Discrimination, Justice, Middle East, Lisbon N.A.T.O. Meeting, Washington Star Column, W.O.M.A.N., Writing
    Recipients: Etienne Gibson, Bruce Gould, Garland Evans Hopkins, Walter Lippmann, John Flourney Montgomery, Caroline Newton, Paul Scheffer, Rudolph Sturm
  - Mar 1952, 61 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: Foreign Affairs, Germany, Jewish Question, Volunteer Land Corps, W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: Peter Bon de Sousa Pernes, Margaret Boveri, Millar Burrows, Dwight D. Eisenhower, James A. Farley, Etienne Gibson, Caroline Newton, Grace Sims Peat, David Sarnoff, Virginia Shaw, Dale Warren, Rebecca West, Alice Whelen
  - Apr-May 1952, 4 items (Box 38)
    Recipients: George Kennan
  - Jun 1952, 9 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: Garland Evans Hopkins, Middle East
    Recipients: Margaret Boveri, Ahmed Naguib El Hilaly Pasha, Caroline Newton, Kamel Bey Abdul Rahim
  - Jul 1952, 15 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, American Middle East Relief, Politics, Relief Work
    Recipients: Grace Casanova, Garland Evans Hopkins, Harry Kirwin, Azzam Pasha, Fawzi Selo, Adeeb El-Shaishekly, Harrison Smith
  - Aug 1952, 32 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: Arab Students' Conference, Foreign Affairs, Middle East, Politics, Margaret Truman, Washington Star Column, W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: William Z. Cline, Stephanie Dolgorousky, Ania Dorfmann, Beatrice Gould, Eva Graham, Garland Evans Hopkins, Harold Peat, Adlai Stevenson
  - Sep 1952, 25 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Thomas E. Dewey, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Foreign Policy, Middle East, Washington Star Column, W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: William Eddy, Bruce Gould, Benjamin Hibbs, Walter Lippmann, Henry Luce, Grace Sims Peat, Paul Scheffer, Adlai Stevenson
  - Oct 1952, 14 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: Middle East, N.A.T.O
    Recipients: William Z. Cline, Hastings Lionel Ismay, Norman Littell, Clare Boothe Luce, Vincent Sheean
  - Nov 1952, 4 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: Adlai Stevenson
  - Dec 1952, 20 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: Foreign Affairs, Jewish Question, Personal Attacks
    Recipients: Elmer Berger, Walter Winchell
  - Jan 1953, 26 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: Foreign Affairs, Immigration Policy, Maxim Kopf, Middle East, The Rosenberg Case, Vincent Sheean
    Recipients: Ralph Bell, Melville Cane, Garland Evans Hopkins, William Loeb, Vincent Sheean, Elizabeth Sherburne, Peter Viereck
  - Feb-Mar 1953, 64 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Education, Jelke Case, Sinclair Lewis, Middle East
    Recipients: Mohammed Ali, Millar Burrows, Andrew Chancellor, Norman Littell, Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr., Jean Marie Richard, Francis Valente
  - Apr 1953, 57 items (Box 38)
    Subjects: American Press, Franchon Arthur, Civil Liberties, Conservation, Domestic Affairs, Education, Foreign Policy, Germany, Middle East, Social Security
    Recipients: Harry Elmer Barnes, Millar Burrows, William Z. Cline, Ralph Flanders, James W. Fulbright, Walter Lippmann, Edgar Ansel Mowrer, Henry Regnery, Elizabeth Sherburne, Upton Sinclair, Lawrence Westbrook
  - May 1953, 36 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: Education, Earl Jowitt, Modern Art, Poland, Stubens Pond Club, Fritz von Manstein
    Recipients: Whittaker Chambers, Bruce Gould, Caroline Newton, Hilda Rothchild, Lisa Sarnoff, Dale Warren, James Wilson
  - Jun 1953, 26 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Education, Earl Jowitt, Sinclair Lewis, Franklin D. Roosevelt
    Recipients: Carl Deichmann, Henry Luce, Grace Sims Peat, Rebecca West
  - Jul-Aug 1953, 26 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Middle East, Welfare Agencies
    Recipients: Melville Cane, James Drawbell, Ahmed Hussein, Henry Luce, Rudolph Sturm, John Wheeler
  - Sep 1953, 37 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: Catholicism, Sinclair Lewis
    Recipients: William Z. Cline, Dorothy Culbertson, Gertrude Ely, Bruce Gould, Grace Sims Peat, Raymond Swing, Dale Warren, Alice Whelen
  - Oct-Nov 1953, 40 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: Herbert Brownell, Foreign Affairs, Germany, Alfred Lilienthal, Middle East, Jean Marie Richard, United Nations, Zionism
    Recipients: Shannon Allen, George Barakat, John Foster Dulles, Gertrude Ely, Bruce Gould, Eva Grant, Bolitha Laws, Walter Lippman, Vincent Sheean, Mrs. Earl Warren
  - Dec 1953, 24 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: Foreign Policy, Journalism, Personal Attack, Fred Smith
    Recipients: Josephine Blesch, John Foster Dulles, Baruch Korff, Walter Lippmann, Norman Littell, Edward R. Morrow, Paul Scheffer, Anna Schwarzenberg
  - Jan 1954, 29 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: Gerald Johnson, Germany, Readings, Zionism
    Recipients: Nancy Astor, Margaret Biveri, John Crosby, Bruce Gould, Garland Evans Hopkins, Baruch Korff, William P. Tolley, Rebecca West, Christa [surname unknown; not Winsloe]
  - Feb 1954, 28 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Education, Zionism
    Recipients: Joseph Alsop, Miles Bouton, Walter Lippmann, George Sokolosky
  - Mar 1954, 29 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Israel, "Witch Hunts", W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: Kenneth Bayless, Robert Frost, Corless Lamont, Alfred Lilienthal, Haile Selassie, Dale Warren, William Zuckerman
  - Apr 1954, 27 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: Atomic Power, Middle East, Poland
    Recipients: Margaret Boveri, Dorothy Culbertson, Stephen Graubard, Charles J. Kersten, Paul Scheffer, Elizabeth Sherburne
  - May 1954, 41 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Foreign Policy, Journalism
    Recipients: Dorothy Culbertson, Stephen Graubard, Garland Evans Hopkins, Norman Littell, Grove Patterson, Professional, Elizabeth Sherburne, Kay Sisto, Norman Thomas
  - Jun 1954, 9 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: James Roosevelt
    Recipients: Colston Leigh, Dale Warren
  - Jul 1954, 18 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: Middle East
    Recipients: Dorothy Culbertson, Bruce Gould, Ruth Hoople, Garland Evans Hopkins, Harry Kirwin, Colston Leigh, Grace Sims Peat, John N. Wheeler
  - Aug 1954, 7 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: "The Year Has Twelve Months"
    Recipients: Margaret Cuthbert, Marcel W. Fodor, Bruce Gould, Walter Lippmann
  - Sep 1954, 9 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: Foreign Policy, Paul Scheffer
    Recipients: Stephen Graubard, Grove Patterson
  - Oct 1954, 5 items (Box 39)
    Recipients: Stephen Graubard
  - Nov 1954, 28 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: Central Intelligence Agency, Israel, Middle East, Franklin D. Roosevelt
    Recipients: John Foster Dulles, Virginia Gildersleeve, Colston Leigh, Gamal Abdel Nasser, Vincent Sheean, Dale Warren, Rebecca West
  - Dec 1954, 26 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: Middle East, Toledo Blade Column, "Wasted Moments", Writing
    Recipients: William Eddy, Colston Leigh, Grove Patterson, Henry Regnery, Paul Scheffer
  - Jan 1955, 17 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: Henry A. Byroade, Egyptian Revolution, Germany, Maxim Kopf, United Nations, W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: Josephine Blesch, William A. Jenner, Baruch Korff, Colston Leigh, Douglas MacArthur
  - Feb 1955, 25 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: Germany
    Recipients: Etienne Gibson, Bruce Gould, Colston Leigh, Walter Lippmann, Paul Scheffer, Vincent Sheean
  - Mar 1955, 15 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: England, Middle East
    Recipients: Colston Leigh, Walter Lippmann, Hermann Rauschning, Vincent Sheean
  - Apr 1955, 36 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: Italy, Maxim Kopf, Sinclair Lewis, Hermann Rauschning, Segregation, Yalta
    Recipients: Harry Elmer Barnes, Karl Brandt, Bruce Gould, Colston Leigh
  - May 1955, 12 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: David Sarnoff
    Recipients: Harry Elmer Barnes, Paul Scheffer
  - Jun 1955, 22 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: Turkey
    Recipients: Josephine Blesch, Karl Brandt, William Z. Cline, Peta Fuller, Lisa Sarnoff, Meyer Weisgal
  - Jul 1955, 12 items (Box 39)
    Subjects: Hitler
    Recipients: Ely Culbertson, Ernest W. Gibson, Bruce Gould, Caroline Newton
  - Aug 1955, 29 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: Paul Scheffer
    Recipients: Grace Casanova, Vincent Sheean
  - Sep 1955, 36 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, England, Germany, Turkey
    Recipients: Charles E. Bohlen, Karl Brandt, C. Douglas Dillon, Benjamin Freedman, Bruce Gould, Colston Leigh, H. L. Mencken, Gamal Abdel Nasser, C. B. Ormerod, John Wheeler
  - Oct 1955, 7 items (Box 40)
    Recipients: Countess von Werthern
  - Nov-Dec 1955, 17 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: Business, Government and the Arts
    Recipients: Colston Leigh
  - Jan 1956, 12 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: Averell Harriman, Israel, Middle East, Russia
    Recipients: Josephine Blesch, Dorothy Culbertson, Colston Leigh, Vilma Monkenberg-Kollmer, Paul Scheffer, Adlai Stevenson, Elizabeth Westbrook
  - Feb 1956, 21 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: Book Reviews, Business, MacLean-Burgess Affair, Middle East, Russia
    Recipients: Karl Brandt, Tish Irwin, Max Lerner, Paul Scheffer, Vincent Sheean, Rebecca West
  - Mar 1956, 21 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: Israel, Journalism, Middle East, Russia
    Recipients: Colston Leigh, Wythe Williams, Margaret Wilson
  - Apr 1956, 38 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: Education, Juvenile Delinquency, Russia
    Recipients: Bell Syndicate, Habeb Bourgiba, Sherwood Eddy, Tish Irwin
  - May 1956, 43 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Book Burning, Ladies Home Journal, Middle East, Russia, "The Third Act"
    Recipients: William Z. Cline, Bruce Gould, Colonel Mack
  - Jun 1956, 16 items (Box 40)
    Recipients: Grace Sims Peat
  - Jul 1956, 9 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: American Newspaper Guild, Politics
    Recipients: Bruce Gould, Arthur Krock, Harold Stassen
  - Aug 1956, 7 items (Box 40)
    Recipients: Lewis Strauss
  - Sep 1956, 13 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: Israel, Journalism, Middle East, Religion, Suez Crisis
    Recipients: Karl Brandt, Rebecca West
  - Oct 1956, 17 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: Education
    Recipients: Cass Canfield, John Wheeler
  - Nov 1956, 13 items (Box 40)
    Recipients: Queen Frederika, Stephen Graubard, Constantine Karamanlis
  - Dec 1956, 13 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Middle East, Personal Attacks
    Recipients:
  - Jan 1957, 10 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Personal Attacks
    Recipients: Paul Scheffer, John Wheeler
  - Feb 1957, 7 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: Middle East, Eugen Rosenstock-Hussy
  - Mar 1957, 29 items (Box 40)
    Recipients: William Eddy, Hubert H. Humphrey
  - Apr 1957, 38 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, "The Courage To Be Happy", Middle East, Personal Attacks, Edna St. Vincent Millay, Zionism
    Recipients: Marie Alexandrakis, Bruce Gould, C. B. Ormerod, Lisa Sarnoff, Dinah Sheean, Dale Warren, Margaret Wilson
  - May 1957, 20 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Business, Germany, "On Being A Woman", Personal Attacks, Zionism
    Recipients: Kenneth Bannister, Harry Elmer Barnes, Marcel W. Fodor, Dale Warren, William Zuckerman
  - Jun 1957, 9 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: "The Courage To Be Happy"
    Recipients: Houghton-Mifflin Company, Elizabeth Sherburne
  - Jul 1957, 17 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: Algerian Question, Biography, Business, Middle East
    Recipients: Ernestine Evans, Bruce Gould, John F. Kennedy
  - Aug 1957, 16 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: Syria, Writing
    Recipients: James W. Fulbright, Bruce Gould, Ahmed Hussein
  - Sep 1957, 11 items (Box 40)
    Recipients: William Loeb, Dale Warren
  - Oct 1957, 13 items (Box 40)
    Recipients: Elizabeth Sherburne, Dale Warren
  - Nov 1957, 34 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: Concentration Camps, Education
    Recipients: Dale Warren
  - Dec 1957, 23 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: "The Courage To Be Happy", Maxim Kopf, Religion
    Recipients: Margaret Cuthbert, Elizabeth Sherburne, Dale Warren
  - Jan 1958, 36 items (Box 40)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Autobiography, Segregation, Lisa Sergio
    Recipients: Peta Fuller, Gamal Abdel Nasser
  - Feb 1958 (Box 40)
    Subjects: Howard Fast, American Friends of the Middle East
    Recipients: Gamal Abdel Nasser
  - Mar 1958, 18 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Business
    Recipients: Bruce Gould, Garland Evans Hopkins
  - Apr 1958, 23 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Communism, Middle East
    Recipients: Jonas Salk, Lisa Sarnoff, Vilma Thayer
  - May 1958, 3 items (Box 41)
  - Jun 1958, 25 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Maxim Kopf, Zionism
    Recipients: Melville Cane, Hans V. Kaltenborn, Vilma Thayer
  - Jul 1958, 17 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Autobiography, Maxim Kopf, Writing
    Recipients: Bruce Gould, Mark Schorer, Vilma Thayer
  - Aug 1958, 48 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Acknowledgements of Condolences, Autobiography, Maxim Kopf
    Recipients: Vilma Thayer, Dale Warren
  - Sep 1958, 38 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Discontinuance of Column, Middle East, Minorities
    Recipients: Allen W. Dulles, Paul Freytag, Peta Fuller, George Gallup, Estes Kefauver, Mark Schorer, Fred A. Seaton
  - Oct 1958, 26 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Personal, Russia, Paul Scheffer
    Recipients: James Eastland, Marcel W. Fodor, Bruce Gould, Helen Reid, William P. Tolley, William Vischer
  - Nov 1958, 27 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Autobiography, Education, Maxim Kopf, Sinclair Lewis, Russia, Paul Scheffer, Taxes, Margaret Wilson
    Recipients: Phyllis Bottome, Cass Canfield, Jonathan Cape, James Eastland, Marcel W. Fodor, Bruce Gould, William Vischer, Leslie Walton, Dale Warren
  - Dec 1958, 3 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Autobiography, "The Courage To Be Happy"
  - Jan 1959, 9 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Autobiography, Education, Maxim Kopf, Middle East, Maria Rathaus
    Recipients: Elizabeth Sherburne
  - Feb 1959, 34 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Autobiography, Education, Maxim Kopf, Sinclair Lewis, Medical Centers
    Recipients: Josephine Blesch, Erika Fueloep-Miller, Bruce Gould, Peter Grimm, Lawrence Pollinger, Whitney Shepardson, Elizabeth Sherburne, Cornelius Horace Traeger, Dale Warren
  - Mar 1959, 13 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Autobiography
    Recipients: Bruce Gould
  - Apr 1959, 6 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Autobiography, Education, Edna St. Vincent Millay
  - Jun 1959, 5 items (Box 41)
    Recipients: Marcel W. Fodor
  - Jul 1959, 15 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Autobiography, Maxim Kopf, Language, Sinclair Lewis, Jan Masaryk, John Wesley
    Recipients: Ernestine Evans, Stephen Graubard, Mark Schorer, Cornelius Horace Traeger, Dale Warren
  - Aug-Sep 1959, 9 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Maxim Kopf
    Recipients: Walter Heil
  - Oct 1959, 2 items (Box 41)
    Recipients: Margot Johnson
  - Nov 1959, 21 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Autobiography, Maxim Kopf
    Recipients: Bruce Gould, Walter Heil, Margot Johnson, Frances B. Mayer
  - Dec 1959, 17 items (Box 41)
    Recipients: Mark Schorer, Ala Story, Cass Canfield
  - Jan 1960, 11 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Business, Maxim Kopf, Sinclair Lewis, Helmuth von Moltke
  - Feb 1960, 7 items (Box 41)
  - Mar 1960, 5 items (Box 41, Box 40)
  - Apr 1960, 21 items (Box 41)
    Recipients: Henry Andrews, Bruce Gould, Mark Schorer, Elizabeth Sherburne, Dale Warren, Margaret Wilson
  - May 1960, 7 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Sinclair Lewis
  - Jun 1960, 7 items (Box 41)
    Recipients: William Eddy, Marcel W. Fodor
  - Jul 1960, 5 items (Box 41)
  - Aug 1960, 7 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Autobiography, Education, Sinclair Lewis
    Recipients: Mark Schorer, Dale Warren, Edward Weeks
  - Sep 1960, 26 items (Box 41)
    Recipients: Ernestine Evans, Ralph Flanders, Erika Fueloep-Miller, Emily Haberman, Katherine Heil, Rose Wilder Lane (2), Grace Sims Peat, Alice Marie Tarnowski, Johannes Urizidil
  - Oct 1960, 3 items (Box 41)
    Recipients: Frederick A. Praeger, Inc
  - Nov 1960, 31 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: China, Maxim Kopf, Fritz Kortner, Mark Schorer, Women's Suffrage, Writing
    Recipients: Kenneth E. Beer, Mary Clarke Burnett, Martin Ebon, Bruce Gould, John Gunther, Johannes Urizidil, Traudel Waltrant-Schmidt
  - Dec 1960, 11 items (Box 41)
    Subjects: Autobiography, Bonn Negotiations, Colonial Empires, Mein Kampf, Edna St. Vincent Millay
    Recipients: Robert Anderson, Mary Gawthorpe, Bruce Gould, Rose Wilder Lane (1), Gamal Abdel Nasser, Clementine M. Parsons, Hilda Rothchild, Ala Story
  - Jan 1961, 1 item (Box 42)
  - Undated, 84 items (Box 42)
    Subjects: American Friends of the Middle East, Peter Bon de Sousa Pernes, Book Reviews, Broadcasting, Democracy, Economics, Jacob Epstein, Foreign Affairs, Jewish Question, Maxim Kopf, Fritz Kortner, Middle East, Pacifists, Religion, Russia, Twin Farms, Universal Military Training Bill, Vienna, War
    Recipients: Bernard De Voto, Garland Evans Hopkins, Fritz Kortner, Harold Nicolson, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Henry Wallace, Dale Warren, Rose Wilder Lane (6)
  - Undated, 61 items (Box 42)
    Subjects: Biographical, Corporation Tax Law, Yusif El-Bandak, Foreign Policy, Hitler, Sinclair Lewis, Jan Masaryk, Personal Attacks, Politics, Russia, Henry Wallace, War, World Revolution, W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: Millar Burrows, Madelaine Clark, Lucius Clay, Dorothy Culbertson, Harold Nicolson, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Eleanor Roosevelt, Lisa Sarnoff, George Seldes, Vincent Sheean, Spyros Skouras, Arturo Toscanini, Wendell Willkie, Margaret Wilson
  - Undated, 44 items (Box 42)
    Subjects: Coal Miners, Council for a Democratic Germany, Germany, Herschell Grynszpan, Maxim Kopf, Personal Attacks, Poland, Ring of Freedom, Unions, Volunteer Land Corps, War, Washington Star Column, W.O.M.A.N
    Recipients: Haywood Brown, Eva Koepett, Baruch Korff, John L. Lewis, Edgar Ansel Mowrer, Westbrook Pegler, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Eleanor Roosevelt, Arthur Vandenburg, Chiam Weizmann, Christa Winsloe
  - Undated, 77 items (Box 42)
    Subjects: Joseph Bard, Civil Rights, Education, Marcel W. Fodor, Foreign Policy, René Fueloep-Miller, Herschell Grynszpan, Juvenile Delinquency, Maxim Kopf, Personal Attacks, Poland, Politics, Russia, Social Unit, Harry S. Truman, Unemployment, Unions, War
    Recipients: Ralph Flanders, Clare Boothe Luce, Douglas MacArthur, H. L. Mencken, Karl Mundt, Perry Rathbone, Eric Marie Remarque, Rudolph Sturm, Margaret Wilson, Christa Winsloe
  - Secretarial correspondence
    - 1937, 1939, 1947, 31 items (Box 42)
    - 1948, 5 items (Box 42)
    - 1949, 84 items (Box 42)
    - 1950, 141 items (Box 43)
    - 1951, 88 items (Box 43)
    - 1952, 118 items (Box 43)
    - 1953, 64 items (Box 43)
    - 1954, 50 items (Box 43)
    - 1955, 91 items (Box 43)
    - 1956, 47 items (Box 43)
    - 1957, 44 items (Box 43)
    - 1958, 40 items (Box 43)
    - 1960, 9 items (Box 43)
    - Undated, 2 items (Box 43)
- Family papers
  - Joseph Bard
    - Incoming correspondence
      - Dorothy Thompson, 08 Jan 1926-26 Nov 1927; undated; 28 items (Box 44)
    - Outgoing correspondence
      - Dorothy Thompson, 24 Jul 1922-24 Jun 1928; undated; 20 items (Box 44)
  - Maxim Kopf
    - Incoming correspondence
      - A-Z, 1945-1958; undated; 75 items (Box 44)
    - Outgoing correspondence
      - 1948-1958, 53 items (Box 44)
      - Dorothy Thompson, 1942-1958; 31 items (Box 44)
    - General
      - Maxim Kopf's notes for his autobiography, holograph; 7 items (Box 44)
      - Financial and legal papers, 8 items (Box 44)
      - Lists of Maxim Kopf's works, 4 items (Box 44)
      - Photos of Maxim Kopf's paintings, 103 items (Box 44)
    - Miscellaneous, See also: Oversized material; 6 items (Box 45)
  - Michael Lewis
    - Incoming correspondence
      - 1939-1960, 40 items (Box 45)
      - Dorothy Thompson, 1946-1950; 71 items (Box 45)
    - Incoming correspondence-alphabetical
      - Concerning Michael Lewis
        - A-B, 24 items (Box 45)
        - C-E, 47 items (Box 45)
        - F-K, 32 items (Box 45)
        - L-O, 29 items (Box 45)
        - P-R, 42 items (Box 45)
        - S-U, 28 items (Box 45)
        - V, 65 items (Box 45)
        - W-Z, 16 items (Box 45)
      - Miscellaneous, sender unknown; 12 items (Box 46)
      - Concerning trust fund, 4 folders, 41 items (Box 46)
    - Outgoing correspondence
      - 1949-1960, undated, 35 items (Box 46)
      - Dorothy Thompson, 1930-1949; 74 items (Box 46)
      - Dorothy Thompson, 1950-1952; 57 items (Box 46)
      - Dorothy Thompson, 1952-1960; undated; 79 items (Box 46)
    - Outgoing correspondence - to others
      - Dorothy Thompson concerning Michael Lewis, 101 items (Box 46)
    - General
      - Legal and financial papers, 2 folders, 97 items (Box 47)
      - Miscellaneous, 63 items (Box 47)
    - Incoming correspondence
      - 06 Nov 1951-27 Sep 1960, 5 items (Box 47)
      - Concerning Bernadette Nansé Lewis, 16 items (Box 47)
    - Outgoing correspondence
      - Dorothy Thompson and Dinah Sheean, 26 items (Box 47)
  - Sinclair Lewis
    - Incoming correspondence
      - A-C, 22 Apr 1921-28 May 1936; 34 items (Box 47)
      - D-F, 06 Feb 1928-19 Nov 1934; 26 items (Box 47)
      - G-K, 01 Feb 1923-21 Jun 1935; 36 items (Box 47)
      - L-P, 07 Mar 1923-14 May 1936; 33 items (Box 47)
      - R-T, 11 Apr 1923-21 Jul 1936; 22 items (Box 47)
      - U-Z, 15 Oct 1924-14 Jul 1936; 14 items (Box 47)
      - Dorothy Thompson, 1926-1932; undated; 63 items (Box 47)
      - Dorothy Thompson, 1933-1951; undated; 61 items (Box 48)
      - Sinclair Lewis and Dorothy Thompson, 1928-1931; 28 items (Box 48)
      - Sender unknown, 17 Mar 1917-09 Aug 1936; 11 items (Box 48)
    - Outgoing correspondence (Box 48)
      - To Dorothy Thompson, 1927-1935; 79 items (Box 48)
      - To Dorothy Thompson, 1940-1950; undated; 83 items (Box 48)
      - To others, 1931-1936; 16 items (Box 48)
    - General
      - Legal and financial papers, 56 items (Box 48)
      - Legal and financial papers including will, 34 items (Box 48)
      - Miscellaneous, 19 items (Box 48)
      - Nobel Prize addresses by Sinclair Lewis and Erik Axel Karlfeldt and memorandum, 10 items (Box 49)
    - Published materials by Sinclair Lewis
      - "Four Days on the Webutuck River" introduction by Sinclair Lewis, 1 item (Box 49)
      - "Honeymoon Diary", Photostat; 1 item (Box 49)
      - "Treaty Trip" by Claude Lewis about trip made by Sinclair Lewis and himself, 1 item (Box 49)
    - Sinclair Lewis manuscripts
      - "Babbitt" sketches for street layout, 1 item (Box 49)
      - "Dear Editor", Edited by Sinclair Lewis; 1 item (Box 49)
      - "Dodsworth", (incomplete) original typescript; 3 items (Box 49)
      - "The Friend of Jesus" Ernest Sutherland Bates reviewed by Sinclair Lewis, typescript copy; 1 item (Box 49)
      - "He Loved His Country", original typescript; 2 items (Box 49)
      - "It Can't Happen Here", (play) original typescript; 1 item (Box 49)